Why don't I feel like you miss me?
为什么我感觉不到你想念我？
There is an important business.
有一项重要的业务。
This secret document
这份秘密文件
You have to sign it before it can be saved.
您必须先签名才能保存。
What is it?
它是什么？
(Are the Japanese going to start killing the Chinese?)
（日本人要开始屠杀中国人了吗？）
Did the Japanese ever stop killing Chinese?
日本人有没有停止屠杀中国人？
Then do we all have to die?
那么我们都必须死吗？
What are you nervous for?
你紧张什么？
It's not our turn
还没轮到我们
tetapi Chen Jia Ping
tetapi Chen Jia Ping
also work for Japanese?
也为日本人工作？
Yesterday they were so cruel to him,
昨天他们对他太残忍了，
do you think one day,
你认为有一天，
will we all end?
我们都会结束吗？
Chen Jia Ping deserved it.
陈家平罪有应得。
Who told him to be Luo Guan Qun's person.
谁叫他是罗冠群的人呢。
Commander Luo too.
罗司令也是。
According to you, he was then
据你所说，他当时
mysteriously stores japonica rice
神秘地储存粳米
and also a beautiful dream of getting big profits.
也有一个获得巨额利润的美好梦想。
Who would have thought that it was a Japanese reserve food.
谁能想到这是日本的储备食品。
Now that's good
现在这样就好了
rats crossed the street, everyone shouted hit
老鼠过马路，大家都喊打
become like this
变成这样
in your heart
在你心里
You think about Luo
你想罗
I'm afraid he will trouble me.
我怕他会为难我。
I'm afraid I won't meet you.
我怕见不到你了
Just think about it.
考虑一下。
If the Japanese attack me again,
如果日本人再袭击我
then I will definitely be involved.
那我肯定会参与其中。
Is it possible?
是否可以？
Why would the Japanese want to harm me?
日本人为什么要害我？
Luo Guanqun was now a hollow bullet.
罗冠群现在已经是一颗空心子弹了。
So,
所以，
You have to go with the Japanese well.
你必须和日本人好好相​​处。
Don't worry me anymore.
别再让我担心了。
You only worry about the useless things?
你只担​​心无用的事情吗？
My place...
我的地方...
Is the money warehouse of the Japanese military headquarters.
是日本军本部的钱库。
If the Japanese lack anyone,
如果日本人缺人的话
I will not lack.
我不会缺少。
I miss you.
我想你。
Who told you to do it again?
谁叫你再做一次？
He's good, I'm good.
他很好，我也很好。
Sis.
姐姐。
Busy.
忙碌的。
Not busy anymore
不忙了
No, you'll be busy for a while.
不，你会忙一段时间。
I don't have time to be busy anymore.
我没有时间再忙了。
We walk again.
我们再次步行。
When did you come?
你什么时候来？
Mrs. Luo,
罗女士，
sister-in-law.
嫂子。
Thank You
谢谢
tuan Pierre
皮埃尔·图安
safe deposit box renter
保管箱租用者
already not available
已经不可用
after confirming the contents
确认内容后
what we want.
我们想要什么。
What I promised I would definitely do.
我答应过的事情我一定会做到。
You should know I do like this
你应该知道我喜欢这样
take big risks
冒很大的风险
I understand.
我明白。
Happy working together.
合作愉快。
Go ahead.
前进。
Robbery.
抢劫。
Robber?
强盗？
Everyone squats, squats.
大家蹲着，蹲着。
There
那里
hug the head.
抱住头。
Squat!
蹲！
Both hands hold the head.
双手抱住头部。
I announced
我宣布
From now on
今后
every thing here
这里的每件事
mine
矿
now please cooperate.
现在请合作。
Return all my belongings
归还我所有的物品
give it all back to me.
把它全部还给我。
My brother.
我的兄弟。
Do you want to rob?
你想抢劫吗？
Here is the bank
这里是银行
you guys should rob the bank.
你们应该抢劫银行。
We are ordinary people,
我们都是普通人，
Do not talk too much.
不要说太多。
Citizen...
公民...
People save money here.
人们在这里省钱。
Don't think I don't know.
别以为我不知道。
America and Japan will most likely go to war.
美国和日本很可能会开战。
The rich people in the concession want to escape
租界富人想逃
you guys also came to discuss money?
你们也来谈钱的？
Where is the money?
钱在哪里？
Wallet
钱包
Money
钱
money, money.
钱钱。
That.
那。
This is a personal letter,
这是一封私人信件，
worthless, the money has already been given to you.
不值钱，钱已经给你了。
My brother.
我的兄弟。
Look, just a letter.
看，只是一封信。
Worthless.
一文不值。
Personal letter?
私人信件？
Why does it have a bank sign on it?
为什么上面有银行标志？
Give me the letter.
把信给我。
Sis.
姐姐。
I told you.
我告诉你了。
Every item here
这里的每一项
mine.
矿。
Yours, yours.
你的，你的。
Everything is yours.
一切都是你的。
Sorry
对不起
street
街道
Where's the knife?
刀在哪里？
Is it in the body?
是在体内吗？
Ada.
艾达.
Dragon tooth on the left, cold moon on the right.
左为龙牙，右为寒月。
Which one do you want?
你想要哪一个？
What is the difference?
有什么不同？
Don't shoot
不要开枪
do not move
不要动
do not move.
不要动。
You let him go.
你让他走吧。
Otherwise, I will kill him.
不然我就杀了他。
Or I will kill him
不然我会杀了他
see if your knife is faster,
看看你的刀是否更快，
or am I dying faster?
还是我死得更快？
Brother, calm down.
兄弟，冷静点。
You guys are asking for money, I know.
我知道你们是要钱。
We don't need to see blood.
我们不需要看到血。
I just want to take my envelope back.
我只是想拿回我的信封。
Our boss already said,
我们老板已经说过了，
all items are here
所有物品都在这里
everything is yours.
一切都是你的。
You misunderstood.
你误会了。
The money is yours
钱是你的
I don't want a penny.
我一分钱都不要。
I just want to reply to my letter
我只想回复我的信
good or not?
好还是不好？
You're not lying, I just need to believe.
你没有说谎，我只是需要相信。
If I lie,
如果我撒谎，
you kill him.
你杀了他。
Let him take it.
让他拿走吧。
Good.
好的。
You go get it yourself.
你自己去拿吧。
Don't mess around.
别乱来。
Thank You
谢谢
I want the envelope
我想要信封
squat
蹲
down
向下
the police came out of the police station
警察从警察局出来
lower the weapon
放下武器
go
去
run quickly!
奔驰！
My money!
我的钱！
Enter.
进入。
Do not move.
不要动。
go away
离开
Hurry up.
赶快。
Pak!
帕克！
We are not robbers.
我们不是强盗。
Not a robber?
不是强盗？
Correct.
正确的。
So why are you holding a knife?
那你为什么拿着刀？
That is my knife.
那是我的刀。
Your sword
你的剑
then you are a conspirator.
那么你就是一个阴谋家。
Catch them both!
抓住他们两个！
These two people were originally Japanese officials.
这两个人原本是日本官员。
No.
不。
Gentlemen
先生们
hello, welcome to the french concession
你好，欢迎来到法租界
I am Liu Cheng, police chief in the French concession
我是法租界警察局长刘成
you can call me Chengzi
你可以叫我橙子
chengzi.
chengzi.
We lost something important,
我们失去了一些重要的东西
I know.
我知道。
Everyone here is losing stuff.
这里的每个人都在失去东西。
You line up outside
你在外面排队
what is missing?
缺什么？
How much is it worth?
这个值多少钱？
Register everything.
登记一切。
I threw away an envelope.
我扔掉了一个信封。
It contains very important items.
它包含非常重要的项目。
I was taken away by the two masked robbers.
我被两个蒙面劫匪带走了。
Catch those two robbers now!
赶紧抓住那两个强盗！
Leave!
离开！
Don't panic, you've seen it too.
别慌，你也见过。
We don't have enough people here.
我们这里人手不够。
To catch robbers with you,
和你一起抓贼
So,
所以，
what about these people?
这些人呢？
Moreover
而且
and there are also Americans.
还有美国人。
And France.
还有法国。
We must prioritize serving them.
我们必须优先考虑为他们服务。
The envelope was not found.
信封没有找到。
Angered the Japanese,
激怒了日本人，
your life is also not peaceful.
你的生活也并不平静。
Because everything is difficult,
因为一切都很困难，
we are helpless.
我们很无助。
We are also helpless.
我们也很无奈。
Helpless.
无助。
I have the ability.
我有能力。
We go get him.
我们去找他。
Road.
路。
Do not run
别跑
I told you
我告诉你了
line out.
线路输出。
I don't want any more money.
我不想再要钱了。
Now it's not a question of money anymore
现在已经不是钱的问题了
I suspect you
我怀疑你
you're posing as a customer,
你冒充顾客，
cooperate with the robbers
与强盗合作
I have to investigate you well.
我得好好调查一下你。
I'll say it again.
我再说一遍。
You two.
你们俩。
Line up.
排队。
Help me remember.
帮我记住。
Line up
排队
lackey
走狗
So
所以
do you take it after peeing?
你撒尿后服用吗？
How could it be?
怎么会这样？
I'm going to pee after taking it.
吃完之后我要尿尿。
Brandy,
白兰地，
French stuff?
法国的东西？
In the letter
信中
what are you actually putting?
你到底放了什么？
Can't I not ask again?
难道我不能再问一次吗？
I've known you for so long,
我认识你这么久了
Now more and more you don't understand.
现在你越来越不明白了。
What is your job actually?
你的工作实际上是什么？
Chengzi,
Chengzi,
don't ask too many questions.
不要问太多问题。
My original intention has not changed,
我的初心没有改变
we are together against Japan.
我们一起对抗日本。
If you think back, against Japan...
如果你回想一下，对阵日本......
The funds released now are becoming more and more insufficient.
现在释放的资金越来越不足。
Today I'm looking for two robbers
今天我要找两个强盗
good craftsmanship, great acting skills.
手艺好，演技好。
This all costs money.
这都是要花钱的。
OK, got it.
好的，我知道了。
Two more days
还有两天
I'll take care of a pile of Japanese cotton cloth
我来处理一堆日本棉布
Later I will give you two more boxes.
稍后我再给你两盒。
Wait.
等待。
You said that before, okay?
你以前也这么说过，好吗？
Is it true?
这是真的吗？
Did I ever say that?
我有说过这样的话吗？
Didn't say it?
没说吗？
Driving?
开车？
It's better not to drink beer.
最好不要喝啤酒。
Go ahead.
前进。
A ghost who believes in you.
一个相信你的鬼魂。
Lost the letters
字母丢了
so now I want to go to the merchant to find information,
所以现在我想去商家找信息，
not possible anymore.
不可能了。
No more clues about fighters and secret letters.
不再有关于战士和秘密信件的线索。
It means
它的意思是
the mission had failed miserably.
这次任务惨遭失败。
Do not run
别跑
Where is he?
他在哪里？
There isn't any. No one.
没有。没有人。
If there's no one, why are you running?
如果没有人，你为什么要跑？
There was a girl looking for me earlier,
之前有一个女孩来找我，
he gave me the fare.
他给了我车费。
Told me to take an empty taxi.
让我乘坐一辆空出租车。
He didn't go up.
他没有上去。
Left twin.
左边双胞胎。
Say it.
说吧。
Since when did you become a member of the military?
你从什么时候开始成为一名军人？
Thank you Miss.
谢谢小姐。
I'll do it myself.
我自己来做。
Then I went to buy vegetables.
然后我就去买菜了。
You guys wait for me for a moment.
你们等我一会儿。
Thank You.
谢谢。
What is it?
它是什么？
Tonight,
今晚，
we have to go.
我们必须去。
before leaving
离开之前
this woman must be killed
这个女人必须被杀
if it weren't for him we might have died
如果没有他我们可能就死了
a special agent of a special class is looking for us nearby.
一个特殊阶层的特工正在附近寻找我们。
This woman has seen our faces.
这个女人见过我们的脸。
How can you be sure
你怎么能确定
he will surely betray us?
他一定会背叛我们吗？
We have to bring our personal data back.
我们必须取回我们的个人数据。
For this mission
为了这个使命
We are willing to do everything possible
我们愿意竭尽全力
So what's your plan?
那么你的计划是什么？
How? Isn't it delicious?
如何？是不是很好吃？
Very delicious.
非常美味。
My boyfriend has never eaten my cooking.
我男朋友从来没有吃过我做的菜。
So, where is Miss Zuo's boyfriend?
那么，左小姐的男朋友呢？
He ran away.
他逃跑了。
This time,
这次，
all thanks to Miss Zuo.
这一切都归功于左小姐。
These several days,
这几天，
we are afraid,
我们害怕，
if Miss Zuo comes,
如果左小姐来的话
we will disturb him,
我们会打扰他，
won't
惯于
have eaten?
吃了？
My girlfriend has run away
我的女朋友跑了
schools are also closed.
学校也关闭。
All the students dispersed
同学们全部散去
So,
所以，
no one will come here.
没有人会来这里。
You know, we're wanted.
你知道，我们被通缉。
If anyone suspects us,
如果有人怀疑我们
just calm down,
冷静一下啦，
Your problem is healing wounds here,
你的问题是愈合这里的伤口，
I didn't tell anyone.
我没有告诉任何人。
And some days there are too many vegetables.
有时蔬菜太多了。
I also deliberately changed some of the vegetable markets.
我还特意改变了一些菜市场。
So no one will be suspicious.
所以没有人会怀疑。
That's good.
那挺好的。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
I consider you a hero.
我认为你是英雄。
Why do you have to take revenge?
为什么一定要报仇呢？
Let's just say you made a sacrifice for the resistance against Japan.
就说你为抗日做出了牺牲吧。
Left twin peach.
左双桃。
I ask you,
我问你，
Since when did you join the army?
你从什么时候参军的？
What are you guys saying?
你们在说什么？
I never joined the army.
我从未参军。
Who are you?
你是谁？
Why do you want to kidnap me?
你为什么要绑架我？
I warned you
我警告过你
You joined the army a year ago
你一年前参军了
right?
正确的？
Shocked, right?
很震惊吧？
This person is a traitor.
此人是叛徒。
This time the action unfolds,
这次行动展开，
betrayed by him
被他背叛
this time following me,
这次跟着我，
Want me to lure more people,
想让我吸引更多的人
to catch us all.
抓住我们所有人。
I hate traitors the most,
我最讨厌叛徒
my parents were killed by traitors!
我的父母被叛徒杀害了！
I'm Liu Wuchang from the Jiangsu and Zhejiang Action Committee.
我是江浙行动委员会的刘五常。
I hope you can join us.
我希望你能加入我们。
Together against Japan, together to kill traitors.
一起抗日，一起杀汉奸。
Me.
我。
You're smart and alert,
你聪明又警觉，
one heart rebelled against Japan.
一颗心反抗日本。
is the person we need.
是我们需要的人。
Left twin peach.
左双桃。
This time you come to Shanghai,
这次来上海，
are you on a mission to kill soldiers at the foot of the mountain?
你的任务是在山脚下杀戮士兵吗？
I don't know what you guys are talking about.
我不知道你们在说什么。
I told you I'm here to look for my girlfriend
我告诉过你我是来找我女朋友的
Don't you know I'm not local?
你不知道我不是本地人吗？
I asked again.
我又问了一遍。
Did you come to Shanghai to kill the warrior at the foot of the mountain?
你来上海是为了杀山下的武士吗？
Say.
说。
Who are you actually?
你到底是谁？
If you want money,
如果你想要钱，
you can look for my uncle.
你可以找我叔叔。
He's very rich,
他很有钱，
Don't you want a ransom?
你不想要赎金吗？
Order.
命令。
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
why did you just come home from work?
你为什么刚下班回家？
Isn't this overtime?
这不是加班吗？
At the end of the month,
在月底，
so many report documents.
这么多的报告文件。
How about you?
你呢？
Didn't I come back
我不是回来了吗
bring the sweater I knitted for you?
把我给你织的毛衣带来吗？
Left behind at the office
留在办公室
still needs to be repaired.
仍需修复。
Today I'm really sorry.
今天我真的很抱歉。
Actually, Guoguo is not what you think.
其实果果并不是你想象的那样。
Do not take it to heart.
不要放在心上。
I understand.
我明白。
I'm working overtime
我正在加班
Lu Fang came to get things.
吕方来拿东西。
You can't make a fuss
你不能大惊小怪
Ping family
平家
Because
因为
your boyfriend is coming to pick you up,
你男朋友来接你了
I won't bother you anymore.
我不会再打扰你了。
I go first.
我先走了。
Guoguo.
Guoguo.
You have to continue to maintain the atmosphere.
还得继续维持气氛。
Keep angry, keep storming.
继续愤怒，继续暴风雨。
What's wrong with you?
你这人怎么回事？
If you don't believe me,
如果你不相信我
why still send me to perform tasks?
为什么还派我去执行任务？
Your mission failed,
你的任务失败了
lost contact with the organization.
与组织失去联系。
A situation like this
像这样的情况
between sacrifices
牺牲之间
or betray
或背叛
when you persuaded me to join the army,
当你说服我参军时
You once told me someone in the organization
你曾经告诉过我组织里的某个人
we've often been friends.
我们经常是朋友。
Is this what you mean by honest and selfless?
这就是你所说的诚实和无私吗？
You still want to send me to continue the mission?
你还想派我继续执行任务吗？
How did you know?
你怎么知道？
Earlier when he called me he was using a phone book pad
早些时候，当他打电话给我时，他正在使用电话簿键盘
fear of having a scar.
害怕留疤。
So it's suspected that there are scars?
所以怀疑是有疤痕？
Our two peaches are still so smart.
我们的两个桃子还是那么聪明。
Xiao Wu Lai.
Xiao Wu Lai.
You guys go out first.
你们先出去吧。
There's something I want to say to the Left Twin.
我有话想对左双说。
Good.
好的。
Your analysis of the secret letter is very good.
你对密信的分析非常好。
I will report to Guan Yongshan.
I will report to Guan Yongshan.
Unfortunately we don't have the chance anymore.
不幸的是我们已经没有机会了。
No, we still have a chance.
不，我们还有机会。
This is
这是
the recent one
最近的一个
just received it.
刚刚收到。
The identity of the sender is unknown,
发件人身份不明，
but very clear
但很清楚
they've found our television station
他们找到了我们的电视台
and also report to us on the same frequency
并以同样的频率向我们报告
This is the password for changing positions
这是换仓密码
encryption method like this
像这样的加密方法
people rarely use it.
人们很少使用它。
So you can be sure,
所以你可以确定，
they still don't know our latest password.
他们仍然不知道我们最新的密码。
It shouldn't be our person
不应该是我们的人
has it been solved yet?
问题解决了吗？
it's been solved
已经解决了
above is written
上面写着
password has not been retrieved
密码尚未找回
The secret letter is still in the hands of the foot of the mountain.
密信至今仍在山脚下手中。
Is this a trap from the foot of the mountain?
这是从山脚下来的陷阱吗？
I do not think so.
我不这么认为。
If under the mountain finds our radio station,
如果山下找到我们的广播电台，
he can immediately find our communications station
他可以立即找到我们的通讯站
directly search for our communications station.
直接搜索我们的通讯站。
If this is the case, our blow will be bigger
如果真是这样的话，我们的打击就会更大
there's no need to set a trap like this
没必要设置这样的陷阱
this person really understands the foot of the mountain
此人真懂山脚
and also deliberately helps us.
还故意帮助我们。
Who's he?
他是谁？
But no matter who he is,
但无论他是谁，
as far as I know,
据我所知，
This information is reliable
此信息可靠
but now I can't go back to the business shop anymore.
但现在我已经不能再去营业店了。
Especially meeting people under the mountain
尤其是在山下遇见人
I see you are worried about Chen Jia Ping, right?
我看你是担心陈家平吧？
No
不
you also know
你也知道
I hate traitors the most,
我最讨厌叛徒
there is nothing better, according to your wishes.
没有什么比这更好的了，按照你的意愿。
After the mission is completed,
任务完成后，
you can kill this bastard!
你可以杀了这个混蛋！
You must always remind yourself.
你必须时刻提醒自己。
Chen Jiaping works for the Japanese.
陈家平为日本人工作。
He is our enemy
他是我们的敌人
you should know,
你应该知道，
Your unexpected meeting is a golden opportunity.
你的意外遇见是一个千载难逢的机会。
You have to make the best use of it.
你必须充分利用它。
Taking advantage of that intelligence post
利用那个情报站
to complete our task.
来完成我们的任务。
Xiao Hu is dead.
小胡死了。
Da Xuan is also dead.
大轩也死了。
But until now
但直到现在
You didn't mention them a word
你只字未提他们
in your mouth there is only a mission.
你的嘴里只有使命。
Task.
任务。
Mission.
使命。
Left twin, stand up.
左双胞胎，站起来。
Do you still remember your identity?
你还记得你的身份吗？
Commissioner General Su Zhou and Zhejiang.
Commissioner General Su Zhou and Zhejiang.
What is our slogan?
我们的口号是什么？
Gathering the will to defend the leader.
聚集保卫领袖的意志。
Raise your voice a little.
稍微提高你的声音。
Very good.
非常好。
You have to remember.
你必须记住。
We have no reason to back down.
我们没有理由退缩。
Making sacrifices is difficult and scary
做出牺牲是困难和可怕的
will only make us stronger and braver
只会让我们更坚强、更勇敢
personal feelings
个人感受
more cannot be the shackles of the future
更多不能成为未来的枷锁
Good.
好的。
Don't be afraid of being suspected.
不要害怕被怀疑。
In the intelligence department like this
在这样的情报部门
there is no one beyond suspicion.
没有人是无可怀疑的。
I believe you can solve this problem,
我相信你能解决这个问题
Do you still remember the words I said to you?
你还记得我对你说过的话吗？
when taking you away from Nanjing?
什么时候带你离开南京？
Say it.
说吧。
You can help me realize my dream of fighting Japan and saving the country.
你可以帮助我实现抗日救国的梦想。
Correct.
正确的。
Everything you do now
你现在所做的一切
is to make your dreams come true
就是让你的梦想成真
jia Ping
jia Ping
I am wrong. I shouldn't have troubled you.
我错了。我不应该为难你。
I shouldn't have asked to break up with you either.
我也不应该要求和你分手。
Obviously I don't pay enough attention to you,
显然我对你的关注还不够
but instead it hinders other people.
但它反而妨碍了其他人。
I'm really selfish.
我真的很自私。
Guoguo.
Guoguo.
What drama are you acting in?
你演什么剧？
Besides, didn't I tell you,
另外，我不是告诉过你了吗，
don't come to business looking for me?
不来办事找我吗？
Didn't I come here to admit my mistake?
我来这里不就是为了承认自己的错误吗？
Why admit mistakes?
为什么要承认错误？
Shouldn't we continue?
我们不应该继续吗？
continue to maintain a state of cold war?
继续维持冷战状态？
Otherwise it won't end forever
否则它不会永远结束
and why is your hair like this?
为什么你的头发是这样的？
But I want to stay by your side.
但我想留在你身边。
Just like before.
就像从前一样。
Is it possible?
是否可以？
I'm begging you.
我求你。
After returning
回来后
You have to make up with Chen Jia Ping
你得跟陈家平和好
back to friendly times
回到友好的时光
that way, you can have the opportunity to get in and out of business.
这样，您就有机会进入和退出业务。
Looking for information about mountains.
寻找有关山脉的信息。
Section Chief Chen
陈科长
forgot to pick up today's newspaper
忘记拿今天的报纸
Thank You.
谢谢。
Check out today's news.
看看今天的新闻。
What news?
什么新消息？
I see.
我懂了。
Written here,
写到这里，
drugs all over the city
毒品遍布全城
also lacking
还缺乏
do you know?
你知道吗？
That's because there are many medicinal products
那是因为有很多药材
was forcibly bought by team leader Zhao at a cheap price
被赵组长低价强行收购
Is that true?
真的吗？
Captain Zhao can earn a lot of money again.
赵队长又可以赚大钱了。
But that money
但那笔钱
most of it would never reach his hands
其中大部分永远不会到达他的手中
pull out the goose feathers
拔出鹅毛
also not a little.
也不是一点点。
It seems like,
这好像是，
commander of the Military Police Soldiers
宪兵司令
do what other big action?
还有什么大动作？
How did you know?
你怎么知道？
According to my experience,
根据我的经验，
stockpiling drugs on a large scale,
大规模囤积毒品，
then resell it at a high price.
然后以高价转售。
There must be a big action plan
必须有一个大的行动计划
requires substantial financial support
需要大量的财政支持
qian Xiu Cai
qian Xiu Cai
quite interesting
很有趣
look, you are a gatekeeper.
看，你是一个看门人。
Why do you understand this so much?
为什么你这么明白这个道理？
Just talking carelessly.
只是漫不经心地说话。
That problem,
那个问题，
is the big business of Captain Zhao and the Japanese.
这是赵队长和日本人的大生意。
What about us?
那我们呢？
Lazy birds have no place to live,
懒鸟无处栖身，
you can have it all yourself
你可以自己拥有一切
Chief Chen, I see you are a talented person
陈局长，我看你是个有才华的人
not like playing around
不喜欢玩耍
you are right.
你是对的。
I don't want to live hard.
我不想活得很辛苦。
But I have no other way.
但我没有别的办法。
I must be following the wrong person.
我肯定追错人了。
This is destiny.
这就是命运。
Jia Ping
Jia Ping
Don't eat this again
别再吃这个了
I made a lot for you.
我为你做了很多。
I made everything myself.
一切都是我自己做的。
You see.
你看。
And shrimp
还有虾
I've been learning from my aunt for so long
我跟阿姨学了这么久
you quickly taste it
你很快就尝到了
delicious or not?
好吃不好吃？
Menurutku Guoguo.
Menurutku Guoguo.
This...
这...
This is not like you.
这不像你。
Didn't I tell you,
我不是告诉过你吗，
Love
爱
can change a person.
可以改变一个人。
You eat too.
你也吃啊。
A huge amount
数额巨大
section chief Chen
陈科长
Such a good wife like you
像你这样的好妻子
can still take care of the household and cook.
仍然可以照顾家务和做饭。
Don't talk carelessly.
别乱说话。
We both
我们两个
Not married yet.
还没结婚。
Very delicious.
非常美味。
Delicious, eat a lot.
好吃，吃了很多。
Section Chief Chen,
陈科长，
you are a good girlfriend
你是个好女朋友
quickly take him home.
赶紧带他回家。
Not afraid of others worrying?
就不怕别人担心吗？
Who's worried?
谁担心？
Many of us are still single.
我们中的许多人仍然单身。
Like
喜欢
gao Fang
gao Fang
I told Qian Xiu Cai you shouldn't talk carelessly
我告诉钱秀才你不要乱说话
here, here Eat together.
这里，这里，一起吃饭。
That's right, come here quickly.
对了，快点过来吧。
Try it together.
一起尝试一下。
You eat a little more.
你再吃一点。
Eat this shrimp
吃这个虾
How
如何
very delicious.
非常美味。
Hopefully in the future I can eat often
希望以后能经常吃饭
food made by Miss Zuo.
左小姐做的菜。
That's right, this.
没错，就是这个。
I hope that Miss Zuo will come often in the future,
希望左小姐以后常来，
therefore,
所以，
I can often eat this delicious food.
我可以经常吃到这种美味的食物。
Will be.
将。
Is it possible?
是否可以？
Sis.
姐姐。
If the two of them are really acting,
如果两人真的演戏的话
her acting skills will surpass Miss Han Lu.
她的演技将会超越韩露小姐。
Acting a day or two is easy.
行动一两天很容易。
But no matter how good the acting is,
但无论演技有多好
if you let it continue to play a role,
如果让它继续发挥作用的话
one day it will be found out.
总有一天会被发现的。
Menurutku Guoguo.
Menurutku Guoguo.
You shouldn't come here often.
你不应该经常来这里。
Why?
为什么？
You don't know what place this is
你不知道这是什么地方
so I have to come often
所以我必须经常来
I want everyone to see it
我想让每个人都看到它
terutama Lu Fang
terutama Lu Fang
see how sweet we are.
看看我们多甜蜜。
So that they step back.
以便他们退后一步。
Enough already.
已经足够。
You do a good job.
你做得很好。
I go first.
我先走了。
Liuli Guoguo.
Liuli Guoguo.
Your letter is here.
你的信在这里。
13.00.
13:00。
Kafe Komanda.
咖啡馆团队。
I'm waiting for you.
我在等你。
I checked
我检查了
I've helped you investigate.
我已经帮你调查过了。
Where's the list?
名单在哪里？
No more.
不再。
No more?
不再？
So what did you find?
那么你发现了什么？
I found something that makes you happy.
我找到了一些让你开心的东西。
Say it.
说吧。
Zhao Anini,
Zhao Anini,
Some time ago I went to Lumiere Bank.
前段时间我去了卢米埃尔银行。
He acted too quickly
他动作太快了
However, when you want to get the list,
但是，当您想要获取列表时，
I met a robber.
我遇到了一个强盗。
He was robbed?
他被抢劫了？
I heard that he was also being questioned as a robber.
听说他也被当作强盗审问了。
Even beaten.
甚至挨打。
Aren't you happy?
你不高兴吗？
This is really good news.
这真是个好消息。
Isn't it quite a coincidence?
这不是很巧合吗？
Why was it robbed?
为何被盗？
Komandan Luo.
Komandan Luo.
You said you wouldn't.
你说过你不会的。
No, these are not CCP people, right?
不，这些人都不是中共人吧？
enough already
已经足够
this problem,
这个问题，
did not fall into Zhao An's hands.
没有落入赵安手中。
Is good news.
是个好消息。
Neither of us knew this news.
我们都不知道这个消息。
Lao Luo, you are so afraid of Zhao An.
老罗，你这么害怕赵安。
This is me, I follow you every day.
这就是我，我每天都跟着你。
I don't even feel safe.
我什至没有安全感。
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
There is no sense of security.
没有安全感。
Previous sentence
上一句
afraid of Zhao An.
怕赵安。
You bastard!
你这个混蛋！
Really do not understand me.
实在是不懂我。
I will kill Zhao An.
我要杀了赵安。
Sit down.
坐下。
You put the paper in your pocket
你把纸放进口袋
This is the first date.
这是第一次约会。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
I returned a letter to you.
我给你回了一封信。
Date me once.
约我一次吧
In the future I will return a letter to you.
以后我会回一封信给你。
Do you want to date me one more time?
你想再和我约会一次吗？
Unexpected,
意外，
You stole my letter.
你偷了我的信。
The one who stole your letter was Da Ma Shao.
偷你信的人是大马少。
However,
然而，
you should be grateful
你应该感激
these letters finally fell into my hands
这些信终于落到了我的手里
I wrote this letter to the Ping family
我给平家写了这封信
we argued
我们争论过
so I asked for the letter.
所以我要了这封信。
If you want to see, just look.
如果你想看，就看吧。
It's just that you don't think it's a business person
只是你不认为这是一个商人
really likes spying on other people's privacy.
真的很喜欢窥探别人的隐私。
When I first picked up these letters
当我第一次收到这些信时
just want to know
只是想知道
Your past with Chen Jia Ping
你和陈家平的过去
and
和
whether you really love him or not.
不管你是否真的爱他。
So
所以
do you know everything?
你知道一切吗？
I just know,
我只知道，
you shouldn't love him.
你不应该爱他。
And he is not worthy of your love
而他不值得你去爱
what's the deal with you?
你怎么了？
Of course it's none of my business.
当然这不关我的事。
Except
除了
if I don't like you
如果我不喜欢你
I've been working all day
我已经工作了一整天
you want to snatch people
你想抢人
chen Jiaping works for the Japanese.
陈家平为日本人工作。
You're with him,
你和他在一起，
sooner or later it will harm you.
迟早它会伤害你。
Don't you also work for the Japanese?
你不也给日本人打工吗？
I have my limits and principles,
我有我的界限和原则，
I will not do anything unconscionable.
我不会做任何不合情理的事情。
Just based on this, I won't like you.
就凭这一点，我就不会喜欢你了。
Regarding the letters,
关于信件，
if you feel deep jealousy,
如果你感到深深的嫉妒，
just save it to read.
只需保存以供阅读即可。
Correct.
正确的。
I should be bigger than you.
我应该比你大。
If you like someone,
如果你喜欢一个人，
openly told him
公开告诉他
peeking into other people's privacy
窥视他人隐私
will disgust women
会令女性厌恶
These letters can prove you're lying.
这些信可以证明你在撒谎。
You probably didn't realize that, right?
你可能没有意识到这一点，对吧？
The bottom edge of this letter paper
这张信纸的底边
there is a set of numbers.
有一组数字。
I've checked at the stationery shop.
我去文具店查了一下。
This group of numbers
这组数字
is the factory date of this letter set.
是该信件集的出厂日期。
Twenty-eight
二十八
one zero.
一零。
Twenty one.
21。
Which means the 28th year of the Republic?
这意味着民国28年？
Tenth month, twenty-first
第十个月二十一
but the date you signed on the back of the letter is
但你在信背面签名的日期是
September 13th, 28th year of the Republic of China
中华民国28年9月13日
the paper is not finished yet.
论文还没有完成。
How the letter is written
这封信是怎么写的
in other words,
换句话说，
This letter
这封信
is to make Luo Guanqun and Zhao An
is to make Luo Guanqun and Zhao An
believe in your relationship.
相信你们的关系。
Make it quickly
快点做起来
You and Chen Jia Ping are not a couple
你和陈家平不是情侣
you guys just want to use this relationship
你们只是想利用这段关系
to achieve a goal
达到一个目标
but all this is okay.
但这一切都没关系。
Like I said earlier.
就像我之前说的。
This letter is in my hands,
这封信在我手里
you should feel happy
你应该感到高兴
how should I be grateful?
我该如何感恩？
However I like you.
不过我喜欢你。
I definitely...
我绝对...
Nor hope
也不希望
your close relationship is real.
你们的亲密关系是真实的。
Is your close relationship real?
你们的亲密关系是真实的吗？
Thank you you like me.
谢谢你喜欢我。
You're quite beautiful,
你还蛮漂亮的
also quite smart
也很聪明
but do you think I will like you?
但你觉得我会喜欢你吗？
Maybe not now
也许不是现在
but later
但后来
very confident.
非常有信心。
Because every woman
因为每个女人
will love a man who can protect her.
会爱上一个可以保护她的男人。
If I don't need your protection?
如果我不需要你的保护呢？
Then I might be a little disappointed.
那么我可能会有点失望。
Maybe you'll be disappointed enough to give this letter to Guanqun
也许你会很失望把这封信交给冠群
atau Zhao An.
atau Zhao An.